Hi, in this last time, I will show you how to step-by-step at your own rules store cursor.
In previous last time, we go through the popular rules.
I hope you already choose to play it you like.
My suggestion as I told you don't copy-paste the whole template, just start adding the pieces
you like, one by one, just feel what rules you really need and what rules you can omit.
In my case, I will copy-paste almost the whole template, and we will edit it a bit, so let's
switch to the cursor, and in cursor you can open, adjust, hide the sidebar, you can open
in settings, the cursor settings, and you can go to rules and memories.
As you see, I already have some user rules, the user rules and project rules are different,
that doesn't matter what project you open, your user rules will be always applied, or
sort of will always follow them.
So that's why my recommendation is to have a user rule, something generic, something abstract,
as that, for example, won't affect the other project, because if you have two projects,
one project is a job project, for example, you start, and another one is your pet project,
and you use ujs, for example, a different version of the art, and then you might have
the conflicts, and I recommend you to specific by project base rules, you can project
rules, and you use rules, keep something general, or like about the style or tone, how you
prefer to get answers, how you write, how you do something, also please be aware of that
project rules, if you store them in, if you store them in cursor, so let's create the file,
and I will show you.
Let's say main rules, and I will show the sidebar, for a moment, you see when you add rules
they created in your project root folder, on the dot course or search rules, and you have
this file.
And if you commit this file and store in the repository in GitHub or GitHub, where you work
with other colleagues, they don't pull the latest changes, so if you have project, how
you see in cursor, and cursor will apply the rules for them as well, so just be careful
with it, and keep in project rules, also on rules, or on rules, the whole team will be following.
But if you like to separate it, you can have like main rules, and you can have, for
example, I would say, something personal rules here, and you can include it from storing
on the repository, like another personal rules file, you exclude it, and you will use it
for yourself, it's some will be something specific for you, how you'd like to program what
your own style, and in main rules, you can keep only some general rules, all your team
follow.
Okay, let me hide a sidebar and go to the cursor, that is, so we have this rule, so we
can open it, and I will copy paste some rules I showed you before, I like them because they
really detail it, the most cases I follow, and for example, the only I change the, I clearly
say, AI rules that he's an expert in these technologies, so, and for example, I can
clean up it a bit, for example, if I don't write the documentation in code, writing conference,
I can remove it, for example, what else, accessibility, like integration tests, we don't
write them, I can remove it, and for example, I can also, okay, like, if you don't use
Redux, you can also change, so let's imagine I've finished the updating the rules, the rest
is fine for me, and I can save it, and you have a few options, how cool, sort of can
follow your rules.
As the first option is always apply, it will be applied to every chart, so all the time
you start a new chart, right here, you see the rules are applied always, and for example,
it's good when you have some general rules here, which you always need, but if you have
something more specific, you can apply, like intelligently, like example, sort of you decide
if it's relevant to apply the rules in that case or not, you can also have an option
to apply for specific files of folders, when it can be useful, imagine you have like
a project, very used like Angular, and you write, you're invited to React, and you have
to folders, like the first one is of old project or old components, and the new components,
and for example, for the old components, you can apply specific rules for Angular, if you
still support and maintain them, and for the new components, for that you can apply, the
new React rules, and that's where you will follow a sort of old folder to different rules
that depend on project or dependent files, you can also apply manually, and every time
you need to mention the rules, like here are the main rules, and you can mention and
console will follow them directly, and just apply intelligently, you can just describe
when console should apply it, like you can say, apply when I'm writing only components.
For example, apply to specific files, you can use the patterns to provide the files,
patterns, it's simply similar to dot console ignore files, so we can use it here, just
provides the comma all the paths, passes the files and folders should follow this, but
I will leave it as always apply.
Okay, I hope this was really useful for you, and my recommendation for you don't copy
paste all the rules, just start with something really simple, and add rules one by one, when
you will be sure they work for you, that way you can create your own set of rules, you
will be satisfied. Okay see you in the next videos.